字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
He fought valiantly against several English soldiers, but tragically
他英勇地迎戰數名英格蘭士兵
he was stabbed in the back with a spear.
但不幸被人拿長矛從背後偷襲
I offer you my deepest condolences, Your Highness.
節哀順變，殿下
He was eating stewed rabbit.
他剛才還在吃兔肉湯
He left in the middle of eating and…
吃到一半就跑出去…
How
好奇怪
He was just…
他剛剛還…
I mean…
我…
We will leave immediately.
我們得立刻啟程
Get ready.
準備好
Thorfinn, do not leave the prince's side.
托爾芬，千萬不要離開殿下
What?
什麼？你在開玩笑吧
I won't do it!
我不要！
Hold up, you bastard!
等等，你這混蛋！
It's your job to protect the prince.
保護王子是你的工作
He was too weak to stand.
他連站都站不起來
Will the feeble prince pull through?
那個窩囊的王子還好嗎？
This might've been a mistake, Askeladd.
那可能是錯誤之舉，阿謝拉特
Perhaps killing Ragnar was a bad idea?
你不覺得殺掉朗格納是個壞主意嗎？
Don't speak so loudly.
別講這麼大聲
Most of the other men don't know the situation.
大多數人都不知道實情
It was the work of the English.
他是被英格蘭兵殺死的
Stick to the story.
別說溜嘴
I don't know.
這很難說
You and Ragnar didn't exactly see eye to eye.
你本來就和拉古納爾合不來
The prince is pathetic, but he might catch on.
他再怎麼窩囊，應該也會發覺吧？
Nothing to worry about without proof.
只要沒證據就好
The prince is pathetic because Ragnar babied him.
王子會那麼窩囊 都是拉古納爾寵出來的
Left alive he would have been a headache.
不除掉他的話，我之後會很困擾
It's better that he's pathetic.
窩囊比較好
Easier to manipulate.
比較容易控制
He's the perfect stepping stone for attaining power.
之後要獲得權力的話 他是完美的墊腳石
Bjorn.
表倫
Why have you stayed with me all this time?
你為什麼會跟隨我到今天？
What?
什麼？
Well, because…
因為我想跟隨你啊
Same for me.
我也一樣
I, too, choose my leader.
我也想選擇自己的領袖
And my leader should be a man I choose to follow.
而我的領袖應該是我想跟隨的人
I'm joking.
開玩笑的
It's a gamble, Bjorn.
這是一場賭注，表倫
If all goes well, that prince may be reborn.
順利的話，那個王子可能會脫胎換骨
And if it falls through?
如果不順利呢？
He's so pathetic, he may never get back on his feet.
他或許會一直那樣消沉下去
Then we'll abandon him…
那我們就拋棄他
if he's an unworthy leader.
那樣沒資格當我的領袖
So? Is he talking yet?
所以呢？他說了嗎？
He's pissing me off.
快氣死我了
He hasn't even screamed.
他連一聲哀號都沒有
He's acting like a full-fledged martyr. This is why I hate Christians.
他自以為是殉教者
There's no power in your kick.
是你踢得太輕了
Let me show you how.
我來示範給你看
You gotta kick someone like…
真正的踢應該像…
this!
這樣！
Well done.
漂亮
That was weak too.
你也踢得很弱
Kick him in the jaw.
踢下巴啦
Wait a minute. I'm next.
等等，下一個換我
That's enough!
夠了！
My God, will you guys take it easy?
真是的，稍微手下留情，好嗎？
We can't very well question a dead man.
殺了他就什麼都問不到了
Just…
殺了我吧
The Lord sees all.
天主全看在眼裡
All the sins you Danes have committed.
你們這些丹麥人所犯下的惡行…
He still has his spirit.
他還滿有精神的嘛
Do we have shears?
有剪刀嗎？
Go look for some.
去找一把來
-Huh? -What?
什麼？剪刀嗎？
Now then,
我們繼續吧，英格蘭的隊長
I want to know three things:
我想問你三件事
the size of your reinforcements,
援軍的規模
how long it will take them to arrive,
抵達的時間
and how you knew we were here.
以及你們怎麼發現我們的
Speak and your life will be spared.
說出來就饒了你
You
你們這些禽獸
will get what you deserve.
你們會受到懲罰
A suitable end
會受到應有的報應
Here.
這裡
Will these work?
這把可以嗎？
Yes.
可以
Captain…
隊長
your nails
你的指甲好長
They really need a cleaning.
這樣很不衛生
Why not trim them a bit?
應該剪短一點
Dear me, I cut it too close.
抱歉，剪太多了
Hold him down.
壓住他
I want to know three things.
我想問你三件事
Like I said before.
我就不重複了
Oh my, I did it again!
天啊，又剪太多了
Twice in a row.
手滑了兩次！
That's nasty.
好狠
Why's he still resisting?
他到底在堅持什麼？
Go to hell, you Danish bastards!
你們這些丹麥人都下地獄吧！
If only!
要是！
If only you hadn't come!
要是你們沒有出現就好了！
You burned my village!
你們燒了我的村子！
You tortured and murdered my wife and daughter!
我的妻子和女兒也被折磨、殺害！
You beasts!
你們這些禽獸！
This is our land! Get out!
這是我們的土地！滾！
Is that so?
是嗎？
We're beasts, are we?
我們是禽獸啊？
Let me teach you ignorant fools some history.
讓我教育一下你們這些無知的笨蛋
Listen carefully, Saxon.
撒克遜人，心懷感激地聽好了
Or are the people living here Angles?
不對，住在這一帶 應該是盎格魯人吧？
Well, same thing.
總之都一樣
To begin with,
這塊土地本來就不是你們的
The first inhabitants were the Celts.
最初的居民是凱爾特人
They lived in the forest and worshiped its spirits.
他們住在森林裡，崇拜精靈
They are the ancestors of the Welsh.
他們是現在威爾斯人的祖先
After them,
但後來羅馬人來到這裡
They controlled the land,
統治了這塊地
but they lived with the Celts and imparted knowledge, technology, and culture.
和凱爾特人一起生活 傳授了智慧、技術和文化給他們
After the Romans left,
羅馬人離開後
you Angles-Saxons took over the land.
最後是你們這些盎格魯人 和撒克遜人來到了這裡
That was about 500 years ago.
那是五百年前的事了
However, with your arrival you brought nothing to the Celts.
你們沒有替凱爾特人帶來任何好處
On the contrary, you pushed the Celts into the hinterlands
不只如此 還把凱爾特人趕到蠻荒之地
and took these rich plains for yourself.
自己獨佔這片富饒的平原
Lies!
騙人！
I speak the truth.
我沒有騙人
If the Danes are beasts,
如果丹麥人是禽獸
then you Anglo-Saxons are just as beastly.
那你們盎格魯撒克遜人也不遑多讓
You stole this land with violence,
你們用暴力奪取了這片土地
so we Danes will use even more violence to steal it back.
所以我們丹麥人會用更暴力的手段 把這片土地奪下來
This is only fair.
這樣沒什麼好抱怨的吧
Shut up!
閉嘴！
No one will believe the words of you barbarians!
沒人會相信你們這種野蠻人說的話！
A teacher hates the insolence of students who don't listen.
老師討厭不聽話的學生
What's this?
隊長，這是什麼？
Now, that I've taken a good look at your face,
我仔細看了你的臉之後
your nose seems a bit long too.
覺得你的鼻子也有點長
Askeladd!
阿謝拉特！
How many, Ear?
大耳，有多少人？
Not sure, but there are many. They're coming from the south.
不確定，但有很多，從南方來
-Enemy reinforcements? -But it's the middle of the night!
敵軍的增援？
The English attacking at night is a real problem.
英格蘭人夜襲的話，麻煩就大了
They're here!
他們來了！
You're too late! You're all going to die!
你們太遲了！你們死定了！
I hope you Danes murder each other!
你們丹麥人自相殘殺吧！
Danes?
什麼？丹麥人？
I'll tell you. It's Thorkell who's coming.
告訴你吧，來的是托魯克爾
He's a formidable match for you!
夠當你們的對手吧！
It's Thorkell!
是托魯克爾！
Thorkell? What are we going to do?
托魯克爾？我們該怎麼辦？
What?
喂…
Did he say Thorkell?
他說托魯克爾嗎？
If it's true, we're in trouble.
如果是真的，那就糟了
Thorkell?
托魯克爾？
He said Thorkell.
他說來的是托魯克爾
-It can't be. -Is he serious?
-不會吧 -真的嗎？
Thorkell is coming!
托魯克爾要來了！
Is that the village?
是那個村莊嗎？
It seems to be.
好像是
All right, surround them!
好，包圍他們
Vali and Ingolf's men take the left.
瓦利和英格夫的人負責左邊
Oddr, take the right.
歐多爾負責右邊
I'll take the center.
我負責中央
The plan is to kill everyone!
基本上就是殺了所有人！
But not the prince.
別殺王子
Also, there should be a knife-wielding runt.
應該還有一個揮刀的小鬼
Don't kill him either.
也不要殺他
He's for me to play with.
他是我的玩伴
Thorkell is coming!
托魯克爾要來了！
Let go of me, you common servant!
放開我，你這個下人！
How dare you defy my orders!
竟敢違抗我的命令！
I'm not leaving Ragnar in this place!
我不能把拉古納爾丟在這種地方！
I'm not going anywhere without Ragnar!
不帶拉古納爾，我就不走！
Relax, Your Highness.
放棄吧，殿下
We only have three sleds. There's no room for his remains.
我們只有三輛雪橇，沒地方放遺體了
Then give him a funeral! You must honor the dead!
那就舉行葬禮！
That's an order!
這是命令！
There's no time for that either.
我們也沒那個時間了
No! I won't go anywhere with you!
不，我不去！
Ragnar!
拉古納爾！
Ragnar is dead.
拉古納爾死了
He won't come even if you call.
你一直喊，他也不會活過來
Askeladd!
阿謝拉特！
We've got deserters trying to join Thorkell.
有逃兵
They were hiding in the hay.
他們躲在稻草堆裡面
It's just as Ragnar said.
拉古納爾說得沒錯
Your luck has run out.
你的好運用光了
Everyone thinks we're in trouble.
大家都覺得麻煩大了
This time we won't make it. Because this time
這次撐不過去的
Thorkell has us surrounded!
托魯克爾基本上已經追上來了！
Go if you want.
要走就走吧
Listen up, you bastards!
你們都聽好了！
Follow the leader you want.
你們想跟隨誰就去吧
You're free to go if you wish.
想離開的人就走吧
I won't blame you.
我不會怪你們
If you're with me,
要跟著我的人
then march!
就出發吧！
We'll march until we can shake off Thorkell!
我們要走到可以擺脫托魯克爾為止！
March while you eat.
邊走邊吃
March while you sleep!
邊走邊睡！
You hear me, bastards?
你們聽到沒有？
Expect to die if you don't keep up.
脫隊就是死路一條
No!
不！
Wait, Thorkell!
等等，托魯克爾！
We've come to serve you!
我們想加入你們！
Your leader's name is Askeladd?
你們首領的名字叫阿謝拉特？
Oh, this is a nice sword.
這把劍不錯
This one's mine!
我收下了
Wow. That's a lucky find.
這個好
If some of his men deserted,
如果他有手下叛逃
then they must have questioned his leadership.
那就表示他們肯定慌了陣腳
Poor wretches.
那些傢伙真可憐
You could have taken them with us.
你大可讓他們加入的
Not a chance. They're trash.
我才不要，他們是垃圾
I have no use for cowards who'd desert rather than fight.
我不需要寧可投降而不打仗的懦夫
To the east!
往東邊！
All right, we're going after the prince!
你們這些臭小子，我們要去追王子
Fire it up!
振作一點！
Right! You're leaning too far!
對，你太靠近右邊了！
Go back.
退回去
No!
不對，是我的右邊！
Steady you go.
對，就是這樣
Slowly!
慢慢來
All right.
來…
Hurry up! Don't hold up the line!
快點，後面都塞住了！
Torgrim and Atli.
托爾古里、亞托利
With me.
跟我來
Aye.
-是
Take the lead destroying this bridge.
拆了這座橋，你們兩個負責指揮
Hurry.
快點
Got it.
好
This bridge is coming down!
我們要拆橋了
Help if you've got an ax!
有斧頭的人來幫忙
I'm exhausted.
我好累
Is Thorkell close, Ear?
大耳，托魯克爾很近了嗎？
It's noisy, so I can't be sure.
太吵了，聽不清楚
But we may have time to destroy the bridge.
但應該有時間拆橋
Stop that! Knock it off.
喂，別鬧了！
Monk! What are you doing in there?
基督徒，你在做什麼？
-Is there more drink? -If there were, I wouldn't give it to you.
有酒嗎？
You're insatiable! Of course, there's no more for you.
連我們都不夠喝了
Don't you get it? We're in a dire situation, monk!
你不懂嗎？ 現在是緊要關頭，基督徒！
Isn't this river a little shallow?
喂，這條河太淺了吧？
They'll just walk across.
他們可以直接用走的過河
Destroying the bridge won't help?
我們幹嘛要拆橋？
Still, we can't leave it standing.
但也不能放著不管
It might piss them off at least.
這至少可以氣氣他們
Askeladd seems to have run out of that ingenuity he's so proud of?
阿謝拉特自豪的聰明才智用光了嗎？
Bjorn! Thorfinn!
表倫、托爾芬！
-What is it? -Come close.
-怎麼了？ -靠近一點
What?
什麼事？
Bjorn, move the prince to that horse cart and take the reins.
表倫，把王子移到馬匹拉的雪橇上
Thorfinn, get in with the prince and stand by.
托爾芬，你和王子一起坐上去待命
What are you…
要做什麼…
Hey.
喂
Askeladd!
阿謝拉特！
Are you serious?
你是認真的嗎？
I have a gift.
這是我的特技
With one glance at a man's face, I can tell who he is.
只要看一眼，我就能知道 對方是什麼樣的人
Brash or weak, clever or foolish.
是大人物還是小角色，聰明還是愚蠢
I can even pick out the traitors amongst the loyal.
我甚至能看出 看似忠誠的人之中的叛徒
What?
什麼？
Kidnap the prince? Brother!
綁架王子？老哥…
Idiot! Keep your voice down!
白痴，小聲點！
Listen to me Atli, this troop is finished.
亞托利，這兵團已經完蛋了
Let's take the prince and offer him to Thorkell.
我們將王子當見面禮 加入托魯克爾他們吧
Most of the men are already thinking it.
超過一半的人早就這麼想了
The others will join if we speak up.
只要跟另一半的人聊聊 他們就會站在我們這邊
You're going to betray him?
你要背叛阿謝拉特？
Askeladd?
阿謝拉特
It sounds so bad when you say it like that, Atli.
亞托利，說背叛太難聽了
He's a good leader and he's done us well.
他是個好首領，之前也做得很好
So we're making him take responsibility as our leader.
所以身為領袖，他得擔起責任
Don't worry.
別擔心，我們逃得掉的，老哥
Until now.
那是之前
But consider what's happened lately.
但最近呢？
He's made several mistakes.
他已經做了好幾次的錯誤判斷
His luck is running out.
他的好運用光了
He thought he lost Thorkell, but he found us anyway.
他以為已經甩掉托魯克爾 結果還是被發現了
I admit
我承認他確實是個好首領
But why did he pick a fight with Thorkell?
但他為什麼要跟托魯克爾為敵？
Brother.
老哥
I think it's unfortunate.
我也覺得很遺憾
But it can't be helped.
但這是沒辦法的事
Askeladd took a gamble and it didn't pay off.
阿謝拉特賭了一把卻輸了
That's all it is.
僅此而已
Well done.
很好
This will slow their sleds when coming across.
如果要讓載貨的雪橇過河 他們這下得花點時間了
What if they cross without sleds?
萬一他們拋棄貨物過河怎麼辦？
Then they'll spend time gathering food.
那就得花時間找食物
Without food, they can't pursue us for long.
不吃東西的話，追不了太遠的
All right! Start marching!
好，繼續前進！
They're here!
來了！
There's a flash.
有東西在發光
I've found
找到…
you!
了！
Seriously?
不會吧？
Unbelievable.
難以置信
-Three men with one spear? Unfathomable! -No, four!
-一下就插死三個人？不可思議！ -不，是四個人！
-This is bad. -Damn, we're in trouble.
-糟了 -可惡，我們有麻煩了
-We're in serious trouble! -Hey!
-麻煩大了 -喂！
Relax, you bastards.
你們冷靜點
We still have distance between us and we felled the bridge.
距離還那麼遠，而且我們把橋拆了
Forget that spear.
別管長矛了
The bridge?
橋？
Who cares about the bridge!
誰管橋！
They can just walk across the river!
他們可以直接用走的過河！
It's a short delay.
拆橋根本無法拖延他們
If that's what you think, then we must march.
你是這麼想的嗎？
Time is precious.
時間寶貴
Again?
又來了
March and march and march!
行軍…
Do you know any other words?
你就不會說點別的嗎？
We cannot win against Thorkell.
我們無法打贏托魯克爾
Have patience for another day.
再忍耐一天就好
Wrecking that bridge will have its effect.
你們會看到拆橋的效果
They can't march without supplies.
貨物移動的速度等於行軍的速度
They'll have trouble bringing it with them.
帶貨物過河一定有難度
If they leave it, they'll be soldiers without food.
如果丟下補給品，他們就沒有食物吃
Without food, they can only march for one day.
這樣只能繼續行軍一天
Understand, you bastards?
你們懂了嗎？
If you do, then march!
懂了就快點走！
There's no guarantee we will survive another day!
根本無法保證我們能再活一天！
Is that so?
是嗎？
Then this is where we part.
那我們就在這裡分道揚鑣吧
Forgive me, but I'm in a hurry.
我在趕時間，先告辭了